thinkbuzan.com 2019-12-15

# Ayoa - Privacy Policy

#### What this policy covers

This is the privacy policy of OpenGenius Limited (hereinafter referred to as “OpenGenius”). At OpenGenius, your privacy is important to us and OpenGenius does not sell, publish or share any information about our customers unless given express permission to do so. This policy tells you who we are, what information we collect about you, how we process it, who we share it with and what access and control you have over your information.

Please read this policy carefully. Further information about privacy and data protection issues including the online Register of Data Controllers can be found on the Information Commissioner’s website at <https://ico.org.uk/>.

This Privacy Policy covers the information we collect about you when you use our products or services, or otherwise interact with Ayoa (for example, at an Ayoa event), unless a different privacy policy is displayed.

Our website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy policy of every website you visit.

If you do not agree with this policy, do not access or use our Services or interact with any other aspect of our business.

#### Who we are

We are OpenGenius Limited, a company registered in England and Wales – No. 05653541. Our registered office is at: OpenGenius Ltd., Tec Marina, Terra Nova Way, Penarth, United Kingdom, CF64 1SA. E-mail: [contact@opengenius.com](mailto:contact@opengenius.com).

When we refer to “Ayoa”, “we”, or “us” in this policy, we mean OpenGenius Ltd., which controls the information Ayoa collects when you use our services. Ayoa offers collaborative tools, including our web and mobile products, which help you stay productive and organized, as well as interact and communicate with others. We also own and operate several websites and offer related services, like support. We refer to all these products, together with our other services and websites as “Services” in this policy.

#### What information we collect about you

We collect information about you when you input it into the Services or otherwise provide it directly to us. This will include information collected when:

  * You register for our Services. This will include information such as your first name, last name, username, marital status, gender, email, telephone number and profile photo. You administer your account. This will include information such as your personal bio and your company details. You provide content through our products. This content could be collected via any of the Ayoa applications such as the web, iPhone, iPad, Android, Windows or Mac and will include information you choose to input such as task names, Task Board names, notes and file attachments.

  * You provide content through our websites. The includes websites owned or operated by us such as our product websites, support website, social media or social networking websites, and any other websites operated by us in order to provide our Services. 

  * You contact us via email, phone or one of our online support channels. When speaking to one of our representatives you may be asked to provide contact information, account information and details to the nature of the enquiry.

  * You purchase one of our products. We collect payment and billing information when you register for our paid services which are processed using a secure payment processing service such as billing address, bank account and payment card details. We do not store credit/debit card numbers belonging to our customers. We will also store data of the orders made by you, your interests and preferences.

  * Other users share / recommend our Services to you. Other users of our Services may provide information about you when they submit content through the Services. For example, you may be mentioned by someone else on a task, or a team member may upload content about you to a Task Board. We also receive your email address from other Service users when they provide it in order to invite you to the Services.

  * You connect third-party services to your account. We receive information about you when you or your administrator enable third-party apps or integrate or link a third-party service with our Services. For example, if you create an account or log into the Services using your Google credentials, we receive your name and email address as permitted by your Google profile settings in order to authenticate you.

We automatically collect information about you when you use our Services.

  * Platform, device and technical information: We collect information about your computer, phone, tablet or other devices you use to access the Services. This may include information about your browser, Operating System, IP address, device identifiers and crash data. How much of this information we collect depends on the type and settings of the device you use to access the Services.

  * Cookies. A cookie is a small text file which is transferred from a website and stored on your computer’s hard drive. It enables a website to “remember” who you are. Cookies are used for authentication, tracking, and maintaining user-specific information (preferences, shopping cart, etc.) and often contain a unique and anonymous identifier. Browsers only allow websites to interact with their own cookies, not those from other websites. The settings in your browser allow you to accept or decline cookies depending upon your preferences.

  * Web Beacons. A web beacon is a small transparent gif image that is embedded in an HTML page or email used to track when the page or email has been viewed.

  * Google Analytics. This website uses Google Analytics; a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). The Google Analytics service collects information on the page you have visited and helps us to improve our services to you. No data which is collected through this service is personally identifiable. You can find out more about this service at google.com/analytics. Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyse how users use the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address which we do not link to any personally identifiable information) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for us and providing other services to us relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

#### How we use the information we collect about you

If you register for an Ayoa account, we will use your information to provide this service to you. When you register with us or buy from us, the information you provide will be used: 

  * To provide the Services you require.

  * To communicate with you about our Services. This will include sending you relevant marketing information, promotion, product updates, tips, etc to ensure you get the most out of our Services. Our marketing emails contain a link to unsubscribe, so you may opt-out from receiving our marketing communications at any time.

  * For continual product development and improvement. We may also use this information to resolve app crashes and technical issues with our Services.

  * For feedback. If you do not object, we may use the information we hold on you to contact you for feedback on your use of our software and/or services, and/or website.

  * For analytics and analysis. As part of aggregated data about users of our website, sales patterns and other statistical data to improve our website, but it will not be possible to identify individuals from that aggregated data.

  * To protect our Services and users.

#### How we share the information we collect

OpenGenius will share your information in the following ways:

  * Integrations with Third Parties. When you connect your account with a third-party service via an integration, we will share information about you that is required to provide the integration between the third-party service and our Services. We provide third-party integrations with several services including Google, Evernote and Dropbox.

  * Third-party service providers. We may provide access to or share your information with third parties who perform services on our behalf. These third parties provide services for, but not limited to, application hosting, server logging, data storage, file storage, billing, advertising, analytics, emailing, customer service, shipping and fulfilment, marketing and security.

  * Business Transfers. If the ownership of all, or substantially all, our business changes, we may transfer your information to the new owner so that the Services can continue to operate. In such case, your information would remain subject to the promises and commitments contained in this Privacy Policy until such time as this Privacy Policy is updated or amended by the acquiring party upon notice to you. If such transfer is subject to additional mandatory restrictions under applicable laws, OpenGenius will comply with such restrictions.

#### Google User Data

We support integrations with several Google services and therefore access, collect, use and store information about you that you provide when you register to use Ayoa. The use of this Google user data is limited to the following practices if enabled:

  * Google Profile. Your Google Profile name, email address and avatar may be used for setting up an Ayoa profile.

  * Google Contacts. To view Google Contacts within Ayoa with the option to invite them to create an account and join a Task Board.

  * Google Drive. To view Google Drive files within the software and create a link from a Google Drive file to an Ayoa task.

  * Google Calendar. To create new calendars that represent Ayoa Task Boards, to create new events, and to sync events back and forth.

#### How we keep your information secure

We keep your information secure by taking appropriate technical and organisational measures against its unauthorised or unlawful processing and against its accidental loss, destruction or damage. The data for our Services is predominantly hosted on the Amazon Web Services (AWS) platform within the US. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number to purchase OpenGenius products and services), we encrypt such information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

#### How long do we keep your information?

We will only retain your information for as long as reasonably necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or reporting requirements. We may retain your information for a longer period in the event of a complaint or if we reasonably believe there is a prospect of litigation in respect to our relationship with you.

To determine the appropriate retention period for information, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your information, the purposes for which we process your information and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or other requirements.

#### Access and Control of the data we collect about you

We have appointed a data protection officer (DPO) who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy policy. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the DPO using the details set out below.

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our privacy practices, please contact our DPO in the following ways:

Email address: [dpo@opengenius.com](mailto:dpo@opengenius.com)  
Postal address: OpenGenius Ltd, Tec Marina, Terra Nova Way, Penarth, CF64 1SA, UK

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.

You have the right to:

Request access to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it. 

To request the information OpenGenius has stored about you, please contact us at [contact@opengenius.com](mailto:contact@opengenius.com). 

You will not have to pay a fee to access your information (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we could refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

Request correction of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

Request erasure of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request. 

You are able to delete your account at any time by following the steps outlined in our [support guide](https://support.ayoa.com/support/solutions/articles/44001514818-deleting-your-ayoa-account).

Object to processing of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

Request restriction of processing of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: 

If you want us to establish the data’s accuracy.

Where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it.

Where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims. 

You have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it. 

Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you. Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

#### Our policy towards children

The Services are not directed to individuals under 16. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16. If we become aware that a child under 16 has provided us with personal information, we will take steps to delete such information. If you become aware that a child has provided us with personal information, please contact our support services.

#### Changes to our Privacy Policy

OpenGenius reserves the right to amend or modify the policies on this page at any time for any reason without notice. This Privacy Policy may change as new features are added to our website or to any of our products and services. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post these changes to our Privacy Policy on our website.

If you disagree with any changes to this privacy policy, you will need to stop using the Services and deactivate your account(s).
